RISHI FAUJDAR

Address: B202, Sai Avenue **Email**: rishifaujdar04@gmail.com

Bavla, Ahmedabad 382220 (GJ) **Phone**: +919039877059

Professional Summary: -

Assistant Warehouse Manager with +7 years of experience in warehouse operations, management, eCommerce & others. Skilled in logistics, inventory control, E-commerce, procurement, and safety procedures. Capable of training staff and maintaining a good working environment.

EXPERIENCE

Novasatum Foods Pvt. Ltd.

Assistant Manager Warehouse Operations & Ecommerce

Dec 2021 – Present Ahmedabad, (GJ) 382220

Novasatum is an Agriculture products-based company that operates in 4 locations in India.

- ❖ Handle a team of 40+ employees, train, supervise, and implemented warehouse policies and procedures.
- Preparing production and capacity plans to ensure the efficient delivery of inventory, service, and cost objectives.
- Managing all inward and outward activities of materials.
- ❖ Managing the inventory and keeping a close watch on the OTIF.
- ❖ Procurements of goods as per requirements & vendor management.
- ❖ Managed 3PL logistics partner for the smooth supply of goods to the customers.
- Oversee all day-to-day activities in the warehouse, and manage daily production and dispatches.
- Handling all e-commerce platforms (Amazon, Flipkart, Jio Mart, Snapdeal, etc) which includes listing of products inventory management order processing, and reports generation.
- Run advertising campaigns on different Ecom portals to increase sales.
- ❖ Track Ecom RTO and reconcile with the sales & returns.
- Manage all B2B orders, seller flex, FBA, and Flipkart smart fulfillment and complete them in a given time.
- ❖ Create reports on sales/demand forecast accuracy, run-rate, inventory, OTIF, expiry, etc.
- Oversee 3PL transactions to ensure all required processes are completed on time; including the processing of inbound shipments and outbound shipments.
- Run random internal & external audits for inventory, safety procedures, accounts and others.

Zivaya Wellness Pvt. Ltd.

Inventory and Logistics Executive

AUG 2021 – Dec 2021 Indore, (M.P.) 452001

Zivaya is a Spa service-based company that has around 10 centers in different cities.

- ❖ Manages inventory tracking system to record deliveries and stock levels
- Monitors demand and analyzes data to anticipate future supply and logistical needs
- ❖ Analyzes daily product and supply levels to anticipate inventory problems and shortages
- Evaluates deliveries, shipments, and product levels to improve inventory control procedures
- ❖ Keep information confidential and secure them with random database backups
- ❖ Use software to monitor demand and documents characteristics of inventory
- Develop periodic reports for management
- ❖ Inspect the levels of business supplies and raw materials to identify shortages.

Shop at Door - Online Grocery Store

Co-Founder

May 2020 – Aug2021 Bina, (M.P.) 470113

It's my own startup based on e-commerce to deliver all grocery needs in my hometown.

- Developing, monitoring, writing, and updating product content, contained on e-commerce websites/applications.
- Upload new products, articles, and blogs and also update website banners.
- Ensure product descriptions are always up to date and work with brands to ensure the latest and correct information is displayed on the website
- Creating promotional offers and checking to see that these are uploaded precisely.
- ❖ Maintain all the inventory and stocks according to supply and update the price variations.
- ❖ Arrange all orders as per the schedule and assign a delivery person.
- ❖ Develop technical presentations, posters, content & proposals for digital marketing.
- Conducts effective negotiations and relations with vendors to establish the most competitive pricing including terms, freight, and return policies.
- ❖ Works as a great teammate, who is dedicated to achieving the goals, works effectively with colleagues to solve issues, and responds positively to requests.

Indore Institute of Computer Education

CAD Trainer (Part-Time)

Dec 2017 – Jan 2020 Indore, (M.P.) 452001

❖ Associated with Indore Institute of computer education, Indore as AUTOCAD (2d&3D), AUTOCAD P&ID, and AUTOCAD PLANT 3D, ChemCAD, Solid works, Primavera P6 EXPERT.

CETPA InfoTech Pvt. Ltd.

CAD Trainer

Sep 2015 – Nov 2017 Noida, (U.P.) 201301

❖ Provided Project based Industrial Training on AUTOCAD(2D&3D), AUTOCAD P&ID, AUTOCAD PLANT 3D, ChemCAD, Solid works, Primavera (2/4/6 Weeks) to different engineering colleges and many more on behalf of CETPA InfoTech Pvt. Ltd.

SKILLS

- Strong computer skills Microsoft Office, Working knowledge, and demonstrate ability in project management
- ❖ Ability to build effective collaborative/partnering relationships
- Excellent organizational skills
- ❖ Ability to work under pressure
- Strong project management and leadership skills

TECHNICAL SKILLS

AutoCAD (2D& 3D) AutoCAD P& ID AutoCAD Plant 3D 3D Printing Solid Works Primavera MS PowerPoint Adobe Photoshop

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

| Year(s) | Qualification - Degree / Diploma / Certificate | Board/University | College/Institute/ University | Percentage / CGPA |
|---------------|---|----------------------|---------------------------------------|----------------------|
| 2011- 2015 | Bachelor of Engineering | RGPV,BHOPAL (M.P) | SATI,VIDISHA (M.P) | CGPA 7.23/10 |
| 2010 | Class XII | MPBSE (PCM) | Saraswati Shishu Mandir, Bina(M.P) | 81 % |
| 2008 | Class X | MPBSE | Saraswati Shishu Mandir, Bina(M.P) | 78 % |

TRAINING

- ❖ Two weeks of training at Hemani Chemi Organic Pvt. Ltd.
- ❖ Four weeks of training on Delayed Coker Unit in Bharat Oman Refineries Limited, Bina
- Six weeks Internship project on Motor Spirit Block in Bharat Oman Refineries Limited, Bina

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

❖ Title: Conversion of Waste Plastic to Hydrocarbon Range Fuel Abstract Attempted to address the problem of plastic waste disposal and shortage of conventional fuel and thereby help in the promotion of a sustainable environment.

PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of Birth : 04-08-1992

Father's Name: : Late Bhagwan Das Faujdar

Mother's Name: : Mrs. Rekha Faujdar

Category : General Marital Status : Single

Home Town: : Bina, Madhya Pradesh

Languages Known: : English, Hindi

I declare that the details above are correct and true to the best of my knowledge.

| Date Ris | shi Fa | ujda | r |
|----------|--------|------|---|
|----------|--------|------|---|